<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-16T13:57:51+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chipotle: Wardour Street - Steak Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/07/31/chipotle-wardour-street-steak-salad/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-31T14:14:24+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/07/31/chipotle-wardour-street-steak-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not strictly a burrito, is it, a salad? But still. Here we are. I arrived just as the fresh steak pieces were being chopped out. It seemed churlish to choose anything else.</p>


<p>This is my first proper Diary since departing Clerkenwell. I am still mourning the loss of my regular Daddy Donkey. But the choice around Fitzrovia is excellent so I've been well comforted by Freebird x2, El Burrito, Benito's Hat x 2 and Chipotle.</p>


<p>The Fajita vegetables are well spiced, sweet and juicy, the brown rice is lovely, the steak a perfect medium rare. The extra corn salsa and black beans were brilliantly balanced and made it through the great hot sauce. Chipotle, you make me happy. The only down side is the cost of the (admittedly very good) Guacamole. At £1.40 it's a bit on the steep side.</p>


<p>Benito's Hat is still a firm favourite locally but Chipotle is worth the small extra walk. I'm also still a definite convert to the open Burrito - being able to take one's time and see what you're eating is a great benefit.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freebird "Smoky Medium" Salsa]]></title>
    <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/02/04/freebird-smoky-medium-salsa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T13:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/02/04/freebird-smoky-medium-salsa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm not really sure this deserved it's own post but I'm adding it anyway. I tried it last week, and it's a good addition to the options, for sure. Goes very well with the Carnitas. It's not too shy a medium either, and definitely has a bit of poke about it. Recommended.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clerkenwell Burrito Round Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/clerkenwell-burrito-round-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T10:28:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2013/01/31/clerkenwell-burrito-round-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"What's the best Burrito in Clerkenwell?" Is a question I'm asked more frequently than you'd think. I guess it's my own fault for banging on about burritos so much. It's not a very easy question to answer. But for me it's field of three. And that's if you extend Clerkenwell to include Fleet Street.</p>


<p>Also my list takes into account the fact that I tend not to bother with Chicken, and I've not had a vegetarian Burrito since returning to being a carnivore. So tastes and opinions may well vary.&nbsp;</p>


<p>First and second place are so close as to be a virtual tie. But my love of all things porky decides the winner.</p>


<ol>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.freebirdburritos.com/" target="_blank">Freebird</a> Carnitas with Pinto Beans and Hot Salsa</strong><br />It's got more depth of flavour in the marinade than pork from any other establishment. The pinto beans are delicious. Don't bother adding the (excellent) Guacamole for this one though, to preserve the clear porky spicy deliciousness. Plus what an excellent hot sauce. A straight up no nonsense parcel of delicious. <br /><em>Pro tip:</em> Get there early.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.daddydonkey.co.uk/" target="_blank">Daddy Donkey</a> naked Shredded Beef Daddy D with Hot Salsa &amp; extra Guacamole</strong><br />Since last year when the Leather Lane stalwart and figurehead of London's Burrito growth abandoned the experimental extra options of feta, seeds and the like and ditched breakfast, they've doubled down on their core product. The Tomatillo was renamed "Shredded Beef" to differentiate it from the Picadillo (ground marinated beef) but remains the best of their options in my opinion. Choosing the naked option allows you to select mouthfuls of the different flavour options. <br /><em>Pro Tip:</em> They're usually fine with you asking to add a few bits of Fajita veg too to mix things up a bit.</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.chilango.co.uk/" target="_blank">Chilango</a> Steak and Pinto Beans with Guacamole, and of course, hot salsa.</strong><br />Yeah ok, so strictly not Clerkenwell. But it's worth the extra walk. When the steak is at its best this one takes a bit of beating. If you eat in you can take andvantage of their extra hot sauce of course, which adorns every table. The black bean option is also delicious. <br /><em>Pro tip: </em>If you're going to eat on the way back to the office, stop at Boots and get some Rennie.</li>
</ol>


<p>With the VML London office moving north to pastures new it seemed fitting to offer a concise summary of my findings during the last 5 and-a-bit years here. Fill your boots!</p>


<ol> </ol>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naked Tomatillo Daddy D]]></title>
    <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2011/07/08/naked-tomatillo-daddy-d/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T11:25:17+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2011/07/08/naked-tomatillo-daddy-d</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
<div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://www.girlcheese.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/p2955.jpg.scaled1000.jpg"><img alt="P2955" height="309" src="http://www.girlcheese.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/p2955.jpg.scaled1000-300x185.jpg" width="500" /></a>
</div></p>


<p>With extra feta. Noms</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[London to Brighton]]></title>
    <link href="http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2009/09/23/london-to-brighton/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-23T03:45:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://girlcheese.github.io/blog/2009/09/23/london-to-brighton</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been a while since I cycled anything like a long distance in one go - and this weekend I tested my knees, lungs and new bike in aid of <a title="Action Aid fundraising site" href="http://www.myactionaid.org.uk/emmas/london-to-brighton-cycle" target="_blank">getting kids in Uganda through school</a>.</p>


<p>I <a href="http://girlcheese.posterous.com/and-we-thought-this-was-the-end-of-the-tough" target="_blank">posted</a> a couple of images while on the road, and will dump a couple more once I can get them off my useless phone.</p>


<p>It was a very rewarding day - a long ride, through some beautiful parts of Southern England. The weather was kind, and we had a lot of fun. As well as burning many calories I'm pretty sure I consumed a fair number due to all the energy bars and drinks I sank - and the pub lunch of course.</p>


<p>Discovery of the day for me was Dark Star Hophead. A delicious beer. Brewed only a few miles from the <a title="The Royal Oak" href="http://www.theaa.com/pubs/wineham-the-royal-oak-374875" target="_blank">excellent pub in Wineham</a> where we stopped for lunch.</p>


<p>The <a href="http://girlcheese.posterous.com/london-to-brighton-route-map" target="_blank">route we chose</a> meant that we opted for a climb around Devil's Dyke rather than Ditchling Beacon. This was chosen in order to make the last section of the ride less daunting - but it was still quite a challenging bit of hill, believe me. I'd definitely do the ride again, and I'd use that route again too - once we were past the M25 it really came into it's own. Beautiful.</p>


<p>All in all we've now raised over £3000 for Action Aid. It definitely makes the sore knees less painful knowing that. Thanks to everyone who pledged support.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
